JORGELINA CRUZ MENDOZA

GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Menifee, CA +951-610-9650 jorgelinacruz@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/leenacruz

PROFILE SUMMARY

Graphic Designer and Illustrator with 9+ years of experience working with institutions and clients on creative projects. Interpret abstract business concepts and creative briefs and turn them into graphics that communicate and impact. Design and develop a wide range of visual content, including brand identities, logos, digital assets, print materials, layout, UI/UX Design, illustrations, typography and web graphics. Manage multiple projects simultaneously, ensuring that all deadlines and project requirements are met. Problem solving, highly creative and excellent communicator.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Creativity Collaboration Critical Thinking Storytelling Adobe Photoshop
Detail Oriented Character Design UX/UI Design Illustration Adobe Illustrator

WORK EXPERIENCE

Graphic Designer

Jun, 2021 - Dec, 2021

Grupo Orlandos, Ensenada, BC

- Designed the brand guidelines and website for Marineros de Ensenada presence in 2022 North Mexican League baseball season, utilized in social media, ads, newspaper, and on-site promotions to effectively drive event promotion.
- Designed and developed a wide range of visual content, including brand identities, logos, digital assets, print materials, layout, and web graphics.

Head Graphic Designer

May, 2018 - Agosto, 2019

Assetel, Guadalajara, JAL

- Led the rebranding of Assetel's, ensuring consistent branding across all channels.
- Collaborated with other members of the team, including project managers, sales director, software developers and other designers to ensure timely delivery of high-quality work.
- Led the redesign of their main website and social media image.

Web Graphic Designer

Jan, 2017 - Dec, 2017

Universidad Xochicalco, Ensenada, BC

- Designed landing pages and microsites (UI/UX) for the university.
- Performed collaboratively with copywriters, designers, videographers and marketing strategists, offering art direction and creative execution.

Web Graphic Designer

Oct, 2015 - Oct, 2016

CICESE-UT3, Ensenada, BC

- Designed user interfaces (UI) and user experiences (UX) for technology transfer projects in CICESE-UT3, including applications, websites, landing pages, and other digital assets.
- Designed the website and mobile application for a water quality monitoring system in aquaculture farms and during live fish transport, utilizing wireless sensor networks.

EDUCATION

Bachelor/ Graphic Design

2006 - 2010

Universidad de Guanajuato, Guanajuato

• Best Generation Student Award, 2011.